<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!--
   New Perspectives on XML 3rd Edition
   Tutorial 5
   Case Problem 2

   Twin Life News Feed
   Author: Kevin Morales
   Date:   10/20/2021

   Filename:         news.xml
   Supporting Files: feed.xsl, feedstyles.css

-->

<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="feed.xsl" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
                   xmlns:story="http://example.com/news/" 
                   xmlns:media="http://example.com/media/">
   <channel>
      <title>Twin Life News Feed</title>
      <description>You are viewing a feed that contains frequently updated content.
        Receive notifications on updates to this feed by subscribing to
        Twin Life News. Updated information from the feed is 
        automatically downloaded to your computer and can be viewed in 
        your browser.
      </description>
     <link>http://twinlife.example.com/news.html</link>
     <atom:link rel="self" href="http://twinlife.example.com/news.html" />
     <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 03:30:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
     <language>en-us</language>
     <item>
        <title>Multiple Births on the Increase</title>
        <link>article128.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">article128</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[<p><b>Incidences of multiple birth pregnancies 
         have increased by 8% in the past 10 years.</b> The increase has been 
         attributed to later pregnancies by working mothers, which are more 
         likely to result in twin births and the increased use of fertility 
         drugs. "Twins and even triplet births are much more common these 
         days, " says nurse Denise Schoeder of St. Judes hospital in Beaverton, 
         Illinois. "Fortunately we are much better equipped to handle the 
         special complications that arise with these type of pregnancies than 
         we were, even five years ago." Statistics bear this out. Complications 
         resulting from low birthweight babies (a common occurence with 
         multiple births) are down 25% in the past ten years.</p><p>In 
         Dade County, Florida, two quadruplets have been born in the past 
         18 months. "I think we'll need to increase the size of our marternity 
         ward if this keeps up," says Dr. Lawrence Jacobs of Miami Community 
         Hospital.</p>]]></description>
        <story:author>Miriam Lasker, PhD</story:author>
        <story:subhead>Dr. Miriam Lasker reports on the increase in
         multiple births</story:subhead>
        <story:departments>Current Events</story:departments>
        <story:tags>news, births, statistics</story:tags>
        <category>News</category>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 11:48:11 +0000</pubDate>
     </item>
     <item>
        <title>Twins and Talking</title>
        <link>article127.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">article127</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[<p><b>Communication occurs long before speech.</b> 
         Babies communicate with their parents through crying, laughter, 
         smiling and pointing. The attentive parent quickly becomes 
         attuned to this "non-speech" communication. At some point, usually 
         in the second year of life, babies will begin to add a single 
         words to these acts of expression. A baby will point to a cup 
         and say, "drink." The names "Mama" and "Dada" are among the 
         first out of the baby's mouth.</p><p>As the child gets older, 
         he or she will add new words to these expressions and will begin 
         to use words in combination: "get drink me." The parents provide 
         visually and audio feedback to the child, encouraging the development 
         of the speech process. Through a process called "echoing", parents 
         will naturally repeat what their child says, proving an important 
         confirmation that what the child has said has been heard and 
         understood.</p><p>With twins, the situation may be slightly different. 
         Often parents cannot provide the one-to-one feedback that single 
         children routinely enjoy. It may be that the one most often listing 
         to the twin and providing feedback is the other twin.</p>]]></description>
        <story:author>Peter Kuhlman, PhD, Hughes Medical</story:author>
        <story:subhead>Dr. Peter Kuhlman explores twin communication.</story:subhead>
        <story:departments>Features</story:departments>
        <story:tags>talking, commmunication, language, development</story:tags>
        <category>News</category>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 15:23:41 +0000</pubDate>
     </item>
     <item>
        <title>Switching Roles</title>
        <link>article126.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">article126</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[<p><b>Role playing is a common twin behavior.</b> 
         One twin will become the leader and the other will become the 
         follower. One may become the talker and the other, the listener. 
         In some cases, these roles become permanent and the behavior 
         associated with those roles become part of the child's personality. 
         In many other cases however, these roles will be switched on a 
         periodic basis, leaving their confused parents' heads spinning! 
         This behavior can be found in other sibling pairs, but it is most 
         pronounced with twins.</p>]]></description>
        <story:author>Karen Kerkman, PhD, Hughes Medical</story:author>
        <story:subhead>Dr. Karen Kerman examines role playing in twins
         and looks at "role switching."</story:subhead>
        <story:departments>Features</story:departments>
        <story:tags>development, behavior</story:tags>
        <category>News</category>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 09:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
     </item>
     <item>
        <title>Chicago Convention A Great Event</title>
        <link>article125.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">article125</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[<p><b>The annual meeting of the Midwest 
         chapter of the Multiple Birth Association was another eagerly 
         anticipated and much-enjoyed event.</b> Almost 120 parents of twins, 
         triplets, quadruplets and even-more-plets gathered together at 
         the Hilton Hotel in downtown Chicago for three days of 
         information, support and fun. Dr. Brenda Patterson, president 
         of the Illinois chapter (and a mother of triplets to boot) opened 
         the proceedings on Friday afternoon with a welcoming speech and 
         new information on the psychology of multiple births babies. 
         The speech was fascinating and Twin Life hopes to have a copy of 
         her talk in an upcoming issue.</p>]]></description>
        <story:author>Miriam Lasker, PhD</story:author>
        <story:subhead>Dr. Miriam Lasker reports on the events at the 
         Midwest convention in Chicago.</story:subhead>
        <story:departments>News</story:departments>
        <story:tags>convention, news, current events</story:tags>
        <category>News</category>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 16:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
     </item>
     <item>
        <title>Twin Tips</title>
        <link>article124.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">article124</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[<p><i>Dear TT:<br /><br />Dressing 
         twins alike is considered "cute", however I don't want 
         my children to be considered objects and I dislike the 
         confusion that comes from dressing them alike. On the 
         other hand, it's extra work to shop for two different 
         styles of clothes all of the time. What do you suggest?
         <br /><br /> --- D.P. Otomawa, IA</i></p><p>The desire to dress 
         identical twins alike is almost irresistible, and you're 
         right, it does save time shopping as well. It's hard to find 
         clothing in the style, size and price that you want, and 
         why double your trouble? Consider purchasing clothing that 
         is similar in style, but not identical. Most clothing 
         patterns will come in different varieties (blue stripes 
         versus red stripes, etc.). Purchase these combinations. 
         Your twins will be dressed similarly, but not exactly alike. 
         You should also remember to go to resales offered by 
         your local twins or multiple births organizations. You will 
         probably be able to make substantial savings compared to 
         buying the clothes new.</p>]]></description>
        <story:author>Lucas Lawson, PhD</story:author>
        <story:subhead>Dr. Lucas Lawson answers your questions on
         raising twins and multiplies.</story:subhead>
        <story:departments>Features</story:departments>
        <story:tags>advice, tips</story:tags>
        <category>Features</category>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 17:12:18 +0000</pubDate>
     </item>
   </channel>
</rss>